yeah we
once across the other lines actually
kind of start with me around so the
question is whether I think around the
same amount every time or if it's like
unpredictable we're trying to maybe see
if it's possible to drive a car would be
better
my strategy is to find the areas where
things are changing the simplest places
yes pesky where it's dropping this big
gaps in those dances the truck driver
really kids there's no picture
[Music]
so there's we say thank you from you're
only looking forward to the part that
looks like this
so once we do a little bit more refining
on this we're thinking of trying to
inject our own thanks is it am I on the
Wi-Fi yeah
Oh Street okay
[Music]
what I've been complaining there
complain all you want the tripod man we
don't have it
[Laughter]
you can't be nice to people on the
internet yeah that's true
if you yeah and yeah it's so rude that
there's that mountain right there and
we're just holding this one that one's
beautifully mounted but whatever after
yeah yeah sorry both its this one sorry
the iPhone 10 - 10 - this is a nice
phone George back from Rome actually
really get it yeah yeah the battery life
lasts seven days Wow yeah pretty good
it's true you know get the iPhone
honestly guys we're selling too many
cartoons don't buy them no George not
always by always by Colin if you wait
[Music]
yeah it's also cookies were also kind of
shooting ourselves in the foot no no
$1,500 covetous that's a
due to and basically the project we work
on with image segmentation specifically
and kind of dialed around the comment a
new dataset and basically were able to
model data self-pity and we basically
tried to classify the images you can
[Music]
and one of the other projects we wanted
to do was to even trade on the common
technique data set but later I noticed
had the data so it wasn't good enough
there was like a lot of missing people
and basically the only thing left is
there was like sighs it's separated
sides from the extra traffic signals and
then there's like three different types
of persons in far away person so we just
ended merger zone with one women persons
one legged person fully yet they don't
have Lane
[Music]
oh this makes more sense because this is
it like every single cover there is
people are always gonna be yeah because
they labor the road
there's quite a bit of difference is you
can see up there that is sorry
that yellow that's inside maybe you can
see all useless passive pcs this
specific video was actually referred
using like the 24th responses but I have
a feeling we actually made if we can
burn the output to how we did other nice
everyone here is also going to be asked
to vote which presentation you'd like
kvass when you camp yourself say their
vote out loud that's so intense yeah
Jake's well I think I'm here to heckle
yeah
[Music]
[Applause]
so I just want to show the example so I
was able to get the image stream into
Ross and then as a result be able to
load up one of my loss packages which
takes in a single image and produces the
death and so this is our business it's a
tool that's built into Ross them like
these are when you get messages this
into boss you have this tools in the
ecosystem so we're going to see that
this is the image streaming from a log
on the right you see a 3d visualize few
of the actual of the actual in 3d space
so you can see like it is quite slow you
see this but it delay of course you have
staying on the GPU but there is a good
amount of bottleneck with the actual
bridge that's because I actually pick up
the messages from CMP not directly from
the shared memory message interface so I
think in the future I'd like to work on
into X this is to go directly from that
shared memory interface directly to Ross
so this is the one I was only getting
able to get the images across I've been
working on getting to a gamma tree data
as well so that peasants
I have able to get that right but once
I'm able to bead up then you'll be able
to visualize the Adama tree over time
two minutes there
[Music]
[Applause]
who's next
yeah
oh wow pencils it's based on take it
detects edges which
[Music]
I can actually just take you through
their demo just here to these features
so this is dedicated like cluttered for
example Russia so this is a quick pitch
strike so let's say I went to this this
is now what to do flat filled we enter
to this so if you have some region
yeah example something at this day so
it's hard to see so I did it as I which
is working on this and I decide to I
just wanted to add these features for
better annotation so what you can do
here is that again you can further put
this and then if you have some sports
left you can just click on the platform
and then you can fill it and then you
can go to a particular image of these
things but one of the reasons to do this
was to go leverage one of the things I
want to tell you was checking out words
github submitted it which is a really
cool so what this allows us to do is
here's some
so this is basically you got a minute
so you to pay attention because this
stuff's all gonna go live and you guys
are gonna label the 10k this is actually
the highest leverage way in a long time
for you to actually improve open pilot
our segment is total garbage that
underlies all the open pilot models so
if you're upset that open pilot doesn't
detect the lanes by you you're gonna be
spending a few hours and come pencil
content sweet nice did everyone realize
that I spelled limit wrong on every
single sign no one no one caught that
limps over there - oh there's one a good
eye okay with that one there's no way
I'm Alan yeah you got us really
[Music]
[Laughter]
- I wish it was on purpose no it's
embarrassing I was like how do I miss so
many eyes so many do I would I know
I'm with myself I don't know what
happened well they do and you think
you're doing an eye because you do the
movement of the M and the T you know
it's all very very NSYNC it's tough Wow
mmm these people are rude about the
tripe I'm gonna shake a little bit you
know there we go shake them yeah yo and
get ready for Carl pencil guys ya know
we actually really appreciate
he's possible
join us and discord for the greatest
common crowd source heard since like the
last one of these we did mm-hmm
no but like this one matters the comic
colouring data is all this matters it's
a lot more well thought out 10,000
images I believe in you guys comp pencil
the reason I believe in you is your pull
request was gonna be reviewed by the
community yeah and if you're not it's
all accurate but all those labels
they're gonna boo like just gonna this
might work this is great reflection of
the common neon sign okay yep
the buncher doesn't know about 2x DPI
it started and first thing can it be
now technically if the Wardrobe in their
clothes so
[Music]
we were that we were checking the old
sensor that's a feature we don't want to
disengage at the passenger remove this
highly concerning but tests already
finding bugs
what's the mountain
and over charger battery is that what B
is no I always wonder that it's like
driving slow oh that's a great feature
but yeah it is figuring out which one if
you're making a fort or something like
that if all the variables are correctly
there's one collection
yeah we found out that after we happy
after all the data
it's just nicer to be actually
we work on we also work on a different
one where we were trying to say
cool
[Applause]
sweet 2/3 you want to comment 2/3 build
a free arm
how's YouTube 58 almost pathetic is it
don't go tell your friends come watch
our channel I'll tweet maybe you know
from people who didn't think that comma
is actually gonna do this we did and
everyone in Disco oh yeah yeah that's
better
okay okay yeah can you do that yeah
yeah we can turn off the me on I guess
two three
thank you very Chris I think so too
don't mind me just having a conversation
you know
probably already linked it I mean the
it's very difficult to make up which
signal to work and so we should have to
do is they try to forget the automatic
filtering signals and ultimately to
suggest from from all the logs from a
signal Rockpile open pi will be able to
know which camp the steering
acceleration operating so we doing it so
we took the and expected everything in
CSV file so we had all the data based a
reference which time
[Music]
actually all I fights all the vines yeah
yeah but what if what if it's in the
least significant byte yeah yeah yeah so
for some of the messages here but at the
bow make sense even message and you got
lucky because in the first two bytes
[Music]
right so anyway after that the idea was
okay so now you see that
can we actually train a neural network
to differentiate between the two so we
go to the file before and victim in the
friend shorter randomly selected hey I
read a few seconds and pass them on to a
neural network actually try to
differentiate between steering and um
steering signals and the accuracy test
occurs ended up being 89 percent which i
think is fair okay not for like
generating BBC but at least in the US
are showing the steering signal yes yes
just to show you what it looks like so I
can I can run this for example this is
like this so of course if you run this
probably is
[Music]
are you doing YouTube how many we got
130 130 they complained about the
microphone
they were complain about the mic when I
talk yeah you're very close euro said 20
percent
oh my battery nobody lasts forever oh
that's true oh I was worried cuz the 90%
more normal yeah exactly and iPhone 10
died so quickly right
so hi everybody I'm Campbell I took the
bus here from Berkeley I decided to take
on this cabana challenge auto figure
printing Cabana
so basically auto finger printing in the
Candida there's information about the
car and normally through Cabana you need
to manually choose the DBC file and
interpret all that Candida and so I
built a feature in Cabana that can
automatically detect the Equality in
automatically applied the proper right
now it's not automatically deploy
applying it but it's kind of getting
smarter suggestions then these available
and then I also went around and kind of
talked to people that used Cabana and
figured out you know what they liked
about it was they didn't I kind of made
some some UI changes I had any more data
to the UI and kind of made it more
modular I also enabled I the ability to
customize there
that you're sourcing here you can see
files from and then just generally went
around and kind of reverse-engineered
out in you know maybe I'm planning on
cleaning up the work preventive on this
and submitting a pull request and I'm
also you know I've gotten a feel for
this app so I kind of want to keep work
night and you know for feedback if
anybody got a new feature request yeah I
really enjoyed it I enjoyed you know
talking to everybody that they didn't
it's 48 hours yeah cool cool challenge
and I also kind of service more
information from the camp pilots that
that were previously available so kind
of you know went through the process of
interpreting this this can data and
displaying it on the front end or for
the ability but kind of manipulated on
Cabana I wasn't able to get all of the
canned data converted into bytes so you
could play around with it but I kind of
got some of the legwork gained and
some of the signals like some of the
live tracking data some of the path
planning data and more of the car
parameters able to be accessed in Cabana
yeah cool
[Music]
[Applause]
one more
[Music]
yeah Mary oh thank you thank you thank
you you know what I want to see just how
long George's battery lasts at this
point that's gonna help him out and then
I figured well youtubers welcome to the
intermission it takes people time to
plug their stuff in you know that we
have to keep you entertained constantly
it's so important yeah but you can't lie
there's some people who lie up yeah yeah
but then people are so mad about the
video you know it's a real delicate
balance Wow charging yeah we have so
much plugs here I know so much plugs
it's crazy
keep talking George 150 people watching
you guys are interested we sold a lot of
two's yeah they're great software did
the interview process very fun I'll
interview myself
fun but
fine fine it's fun it's just fine Joe
but driving chill if you fire come to
but don't buy come to Seoul too many
yeah now I'm done with that I'm done
with that reckless played out limits
without the I was happy is what are you
gonna do to the screens not work when
you want to plug them and plug them back
in Oh No Nvidia fix your driver Nvidia
if you're watching fix your driver way
mo if you're watching shutdown you'll
never make money
[Laughter]
zooks if you're watching we are hiring
we are reaching from a big level five
company today
I'm sorry level four
hmm I think the presentation is gonna
get down here
Oh what yup yup just just the monitor is
uh some things that monitor don't judge
based on that chip that's right
computer because the Nvidia drivers are
terrible going on plug you plunge of mud
and Eric over beer yeah you will regret
it okay
that system program problem detected
started after I installed the Nvidia
drivers by the way look guys manager
runs on Ubuntu now it's like people are
so quick yeah I wrote this code so the
brakes first oh no no you know the
problem is we got to run calibration D
open up another window yeah that's the
rain by the way so dry
she's a location location date just
that's good I'm da / calibration date
Wow
about to be crazy fingers crossed
that's super combo wait is the framerate
right why isn't the model running should
be running right we need anything else
oh maybe it's there I don't think it's
working
no I don't know restart calibration day
restart your model he's not gonna be
bothering Model T is not gonna run the
model unless nobody should from the
model because this super combo Oh
control C model the entire even gotten
into the work you didn't change you I
know Chelsea ma do you run it again
that was not right there click on though
yeah but don't tell Caesar
Oh
yeah why didn't Cambodia least are you
running comedy - yeah oh that thing lies
and says - oh you have health - yes nice
I should start model Deepak it worked
for like three frames this is exciting
who's gonna be the first person to go
out and put a youtube video up driving
with your logitech webcam the future is
decentralized all you need is this all
you need is a webcam and a gaming
computer and open source software to
drive your car yeah and a panda I don't
know that but there was the yeah really
someone having adapter that they were
used yeah there you go
No
we can you can show it on the laptop
yeah let's do that
[Laughter]
so hi Kenzie I'm super happy and proud
to be here I appreciate you all giving
me a chance um so I'm probably by me not
probably I'm definitely by orders of
magnitude the least experienced person
here so at the very beginning of this
event George mentioned two reasons why
we're here one of them was as a
recruiting event to find machine
learning talent clearly I don't fall
into that bucket yet so the other one
was to beta-test some software so I was
more focused on that aspect as a person
who is maybe more savvy than some people
but is still just like trying to figure
things some of these things out so I
guess I was representing that end of the
user pool perhaps but in any case also
George mentioned externalizing things
and so I decided to focus on that Jo
[Music]
wanting to see torque displayed maybe in
the EON but an indication in the
meanwhile I started working on showing
torque but not in the beyond instead in
the in the UI interface so um I'm not
sure how many I'll work on this aspect
but there's the unlocker which we start
running and then it starts spitting out
data and then we can run the UI module
on top of that so
let me just first demonstrate the UI as
it was originally received by me
so Iran Isis currently exists on the
repo so we get the data running here off
of a public route public on lager thanks
to anti-age - yes so you can start
spitting out data you come over here and
[Music]
yeah we run the UI and the UI should pop
up there it does so for those who have
tested it this is what the UI looks like
there is an issue here right off the bat
which is basically that the resolution
of either the VM and/or my Mac are
making it such that the lower part of
the UI is cut off I don't think I have
well it's fine I don't think I have the
capabilities necessarily to change that
I tried to mess around with a resolution
I could not get the bottom part of the
UI to show up but I was intending to add
torque to this anyway
so that is the UI as it exists and so I
started making some changes on the route
to get any torque to show up so I'll
just quickly go through these I know
what these invasive so the short
presentation so the first thought I had
was making it resizable I started
digging around in the UI and also one of
the UI libraries and I was able to make
it resizable but that did not make it
such that you can scroll things I've
done the next thing which is that okay
so I have a screenshot here of the UI
where you can see that UI is five years
old now oh yeah I wrote that during the
smoking weed era of common
[Laughter]
so here's a speech I made of the next
part which is that I was started messing
around the elements and I appreciate
very parsimonious commenting I think
that's an under best circumstances an
indicative of good coding and so that
was the case here sorry how did you
start manipulating things to see what
was what
so first thing I found is that this text
was the thing that was off-screen so I
changed the orientation to be zero zero
so that I could see the text and it
looks better on the picture there looks
like the tehsil ones I agree yeah that's
that's one of the things I realized so
thanks Tesla
so yeah so this text which is not
visible on the UI with my current setup
is now visible and I agree with George
it does look better with the picture as
the background so but then I noticed
there's this new line break between
those two sets of data so I asked Gregg
is there a reason for that because you
can see actually apparently one of the
ways in the smoking weed era to show my
break is to just do none and that added
the line break so but clearly that was
an atom for no reason so I asked great
great what the reason was he wasn't
quite sure but he guessed that there is
some sort of categorical separation
there so in an attempt to retain the
category separation categorical
separation without without having a new
line there because it was taking it more
space I just removed the new line and
then change this lower frost to orange
had to find out how to do all that and
was successful and there's gonna be sort
of a reveal at the end or whatever I
just show you all that change limit
anyway give us the reveal in one minute
ok ok other other change I did was there
was there's a video that shows the
trajectories on top of the area of
interest and I wanted to put that up
here because there's a lot of wasted
space just from a usability perspective
there's a lot of wasted space going on
up here and basically anything outside
of the bounding box we don't really care
about so from a visual perspective it's
better just to have it in there so I
kept this text
move it over here get it up here put
that put the other box up here to the
divinium video which is a shout out of
it and then yeah and then starting
something massaging text moving things
around massages and then the plot moves
out of the way so I started massaging
plot spacing in my UI oh so so yeah so
now we have the video in video so as
we're taking advantage of the wasted
space above all so it's aligned with the
image below in order to basically have a
little easier visual acuity this is
still taking advantage of being on top
of the background and now because the
default setting on the text for enabled
and brake light is black we can actually
see you know when it's not being engaged
effectively also I moved this map up so
we can make sure and see the car and the
reason why this text is alright to
overlap is because the farther we get
away from the front of the car the less
is effectively so it doesn't really
enjoin the on the you whatever the
debugging aspect of which is what we're
using this for and then I got the plot I
you know matplotlib as we all know is
not easy to use but I was able to
massage these into space so that we're
still seeing the data and the last thing
that I was working on but wasn't able to
do was get these labels to match the
color of the gas line that would seem to
be that makes a lot more sense than a
little parenthesis that we have the UI
has not been shown much longer okay so
now the very last that was that was
that's mostly what I did and then the
very last little thing is that as we can
see here with this system is based on
pygame and pygame
works quite well but here's the thing
pygame quite understandably has self
promotion needs and so as you can see
every time we invoke the UI piking gets
their little
husband in that hello from the PI game
community which is overwhelming you know
okay well so then I didn't like that I
don't want I mean no offense the flag
game we love them and all that but I
just personally didn't want to see that
so I first got rid of it and I thought
no but we still want to prompt so I
added a combo prompt everyone in 2%
preventer no no all right I said we were
gonna shout it out but we're not really
gonna oh well actually gonna all go in
the back home employees after this and
decide who wins the prizes oh we can't
be bribed yeah but you're do that
dashboard
people love dashboards I don't know why
and so basically what I did
2092 k-19 and flipped around the process
readers to a non processed readers it's
running currently on a branch and might
get a hackathon if you want to get a
ticket do whatever you want with it but
it's really cute I to be aware of that
instead of numpy basically we're just
burning all of everything this one it
should be what is that
yes we're downloading the entire 22 K 19
data set right and then we go and we
extract all the values which was kind of
hard to do but that's good so I just
simplify the whole bunch for loops and
then I brought them in and I made a
dashboard which doesn't really work but
should eventually we have some display
issues around saying there's a for some
reason and so you just go down here just
running off iPod widgets as well a few
other simple technologies and you should
be let's do just put spacer and we'll
get the full dear friend there with the
query and then we can do is coordinate
map which is not gonna be out
it was taken I like this one I think we
can do better and I think we can scale
it and then the speed verse bearing just
to show it's kind of possible and this
is the Geo map to show that a map was
supposed to be there but I couldn't get
a display that's all hey yeah could you
tell people to get their asking you okey
whoa cool
okay um so remember how I said YouTube
was gonna come in the back to the
judgment session they're not sorry you
two bye bye you two
[Music]